citrix.com 2014-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Citrix

#### Last Updated: December 13, 2013

Citrix respects your privacy and is committed to protecting the personal information you share with us. This Privacy Policy describes how Citrix collects and uses your personal information to provide products, services and information that you request or when you choose to provide us with your personal information.

#### Scope

This Privacy Statement covers privacy practices for www.citrix.com, as well as Citrix’s mobile applications listed below. When visiting web sites of Citrix divisions or its wholly-owned subsidiaries, please review the applicable privacy policies disclosed on those sites.

#### Personal Information

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, email address, telephone number, postal or other physical address, other contact information, title, occupation, work industry, and other information which may be required by Citrix to provide products, services, and information to you.

#### Information Collection

When you browse our website, you do so anonymously, unless you have previously registered with us. We do collect IP (Internet Protocol) addresses of computers for the purpose of maintaining and improving site quality and integrity. This log is a standard method of reporting in order to statistically determine which parts of our website are visited and how long visitors spend there. We also log the type of browser and operating system you are using. We do not automatically collect other personal information, such as your email address.

Like many other commercial websites, the Citrix website may use a standard technology called a “cookie” to collect information about how you use the site. Please go to “Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies” below for more information.

At times we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information for purposes such as:

  * when you register with Citrix for a MyCitrix account;
  * when you register as a partner;
  * when you register an online program, event, seminars, promotions or sweepstakes;
  * when you request product (including but not limited to product evaluation, tech preview and beta downloads), services or information;
  * when you participate in Citrix events, surveys, questionnaire or evaluation; or
  * otherwise correspond with us or request information from us.  

In addition, from time to time, Citrix receives personal information from business partners and vendors. Citrix only uses such information for purposes as specified herein if Citrix reasonably believes that it has been duly collected in accordance with applicable laws.

#### How We Use Information Collected

Citrix may use personal information to provide customers and business partners with information and services and to help us better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, we may use your information to help you complete a transaction or order, to communicate with you, to deliver products/services to you, to bill you for products/services you purchased, and to provide ongoing service and support. Occasionally we may use your information to contact you to complete surveys that we use for quality assurance purposes.

We may also use your personal information to send you, or to have our business partners or marketing agencies send you, direct marketing information or contact you for marketing research. Where required by local legislation, we will provide you with the opportunity to “opt in” prior to receiving direct marketing information. At a minimum, we will always give you the opportunity to “opt out” of receiving materials you choose to unsubscribe.

#### Information Sharing and Disclosure

As Citrix is a global company, your personal information may be shared with other Citrix offices or subsidiaries around the world. In such case, the entities concerned are governed by this Privacy Policy.

Within Citrix, data is stored in controlled servers with restricted access. Your personal information may be stored and processed worldwide in the global offices of Citrix or its marketing agents. Unless otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy, your personal information is not shared outside Citrix without your permission.

Citrix may send your personal information to other companies or people under any of the following circumstances:

  * When we have your consent to share the information (if required under local law);
  * If sharing your information is necessary to provide a product, service or information you have requested; by way of example, sharing your information with a bank, logistics company, event organizer, marketing agency etc;
  * As part of a joint sales promotion or to pass sales leads to our business partners;
  * To keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, special offers or other information we think you would like to hear about either from us, through our marketing agencies or from our business partners;
  * For the purpose of conducting US Export law compliance checks, passing your information to our contracted vendors;
  * For data and customer relations management, passing your data to our contracted service providers.

We reserve our right to disclose your personal information to a third party if we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable Legal Notice and Terms of Use, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Citrix, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.

#### Mobile Applications

Citrix XenMobile applications may collect personally identifiable information, geo-location data or personal usage statistics on behalf of our XenMobile MDM customers. For specific information on your company’s mobile device management data practices and policy, please contact your company’s mobile device Administrator. Citrix only receives aggregated and anonymous download and mobile application usage statistics for purposes of analysis. We do not correlate this information with personally identifiable data about individual end users. Citrix XenMobile mobile applications do not utilize third party web analytical tools. The XenMobile MDM solution is delivered as either an on-premise mobile device management server or a cloud solution. For the Citrix hosted cloud solution, Citrix will only view end-user data as necessary to support maintenance operations of the service or for the purpose of anticipating, diagnosing or resolving any problems that might limit or disrupt the quality of our customers’ experience.

#### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Cookies, web beacons and/or similar devices were originally designed to help a website distinguish a user’s browser from a previous visitor and thus save and remember any preferences that may have been set while the user was browsing the site or to track the user’s activities. A cookie is a small string of text that a website can send to your browser. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on computer viruses, or capture your email address. Currently, Citrix uses cookies to enhance the user’s visit; in general, cookies can securely store a user’s ID and password, personalize home pages, identify which parts of a site have been visited or keep track of selections. A web beacon is a small transparent gif image that is embedded in an HTML page or email used to track when the page or email has been viewed. A similar device may be used by which a product or service may send data to a server when a set of user-initiated events occur such as when a selection is made. This device is similar to a cookie in that it tracks your visit and the data can only be read by the server that receives the data. It is different than a cookie in that it is not browser-based, may not function as an identification card, and does not store any data on your computer. If you wish to not have the information these technologies collect used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether.

If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website or via HTML-formatted emails, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, although you may not be able to take full advantage of Citrix’s website if you do so. In particular, you may be required to accept cookies in order to complete certain actions on our website. To use/navigate through many parts of our website, you do not need to turn on cookies.

#### Your Ability to Access or Change Your Information

If you are a registered user or have been named as a “Contact” for a company (including but not limited to companies acting as our end users or partners), you can review your personal information and make change requests by accessing My Account. While you are named as the “Contact” for a particular company, Citrix will direct to you many of the correspondences for such company. If you do not wish to receive further business correspondence for and on behalf of your company, you may change the “Contact” to another individual upon consultation with your company. In the alternative, if you do not wish to receive further direct marketing materials, you may “unsubscribe” the relevant marketing materials. If you are no longer the “Contact” for a particular company, we will retain in our files some personal information to prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, enforce our Legal Notice and Terms of Use, respect your opt-out preferences, and comply with legal requirements as permitted by law.

#### Personal Information Security

Your Citrix account information is protected for your privacy. Citrix safeguards the personal information you send us and takes reasonable physical, technical, and organizational measures to prevent unauthorized access, unlawful processing, and unauthorized or accidental loss, destruction, or damage to your personal information. Citrix uses industry-standard SSL-encryption to enhance the security of sensitive data transmissions in most of our websites. While we strive to protect your personal information, we need your co-operation to ensure the security of the information you transmit to us. We urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal information while using the Internet. Change your passwords often, use a passphrase instead of password with at least 8 characters in combination of letters and numbers and try to adhere to Microsoft’s password complexity requirements. Make sure you use a secure internet browser, follow the vendor suggestion and apply updates when required.

#### Children and Privacy

Citrix’s product ad campaigns and marketing materials are intended to be viewed by adults over 18 years of age. We do not intend to receive personal information from children.

#### Third Party Sites

Our website may contain links to websites operated by other companies. Some of these third-party sites may be co-branded with a Citrix logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by Citrix. Citrix does not share your personal information with those websites and is not responsible for their privacy practices. Once you have left our website, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party website to determine how they will handle any information they collect from you.

#### Forums and Blogs

Some of Citrix’s websites allow our users to publish content via discussion forums, blogs, and other means. Any information that is disclosed in these forums becomes public information which could be read, collected or used by other users to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

Citrix may, from time to time, send emails regarding our products and services to users who have published content through our websites. Each participant’s opinion expressed is his or her own and should not be considered as reflecting the opinion of Citrix. Note also that your use of these online communication tools is subject to our Terms of Use. Personal information given to Citrix may be transferred across state and country borders for data consolidation, storage and simplified information management.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Citrix will amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes of this Privacy Policy, we will make that information available by posting a notice on this site.

#### Questions or Suggestions

If you have questions or concerns about our collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information, please [contact us](http://deliver.citrix.com/go/citrix/privacyinquiry).

**Citrix Systems, Inc.**  
851 West Cypress Creek Road  
Fort Lauderdale, FL 33309
